You're travelling through another dimension. A dimension, not only of sight and sound, but of mind. A journey
into a wondrous land whose boundaries are that of imagination. Next stop, the Twilight Zone!
Twilight Zone: The Movie is a horror, fantasy, science
fiction film directed by John Landis.
An anthology film presenting remakes of three episodes from the "Twilight Zone" TV series—"Kick the
Can", "It's a Good Life" and "Nightmare at 20,000 Feet"—and one original story, "Time Out."
Passenger, played by Dan Aykroyd.
Driver, played by Albert Brooks.
Mr. Bloom, played by Scatman Crothers.
Valentine, played by John Lithgow.
Bill, played by Vic Morrow.
Helen Foley, played by Kathleen Quinlan.
Twilight Zone: The Movie is a 1983 American sci-fi fantasy horror
anthology film produced by Steven Spielberg and John Landis.
Based on Rod Serling's 1959–1964 television series of the same name, the film features
four stories directed by Landis, Spielberg, Joe Dante, and George Miller.
Landis' segment is an original story created for the film, while the segments by
Spielberg, Dante, and Miller are remakes of episodes from the original series.
The film's cast includes Dan Aykroyd, Albert Brooks, Scatman
Crothers, John Lithgow, Vic Morrow, and Kathleen Quinlan.
Original series cast members Burgess Meredith, Patricia Barry, Peter Brocco, Murray Matheson, Kevin McCarthy, Bill
Mumy, and William Schallert also appear in the film, with Meredith assuming Serling's role as narrator.
The film's production achieved notoriety when Morrow and two illegally hired child actors
were killed in a helicopter crash during the filming of Landis's segment.
The deaths led to several years of legal action; although no individuals were found to be criminally
liable, new procedures and safety standards were imposed in the filmmaking industry.
Upon release by Warner Bros.
on June 24, 1983, the film received mixed reviews, with praise directed at Dante and
Miller's segments, but criticism towards the segments by Landis and Spielberg.
Despite the controversy and mixed reception, it was a commercial
success, grossing $42 million on a $10 million budget.
The film explores themes of nazi, anthology, remake, mysterious, zone.
The tone is dark and thought_provoking and intense.